hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak and
remember to sign up for our one dollar
listening practice seminars at
polyglossa.com
and download my free listening time
podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about middle
school
in the u.s this is the level of school
that comes
after elementary school and before high
school
this is an interesting period in a
person's life
and in their academic career so let's
talk about it
first of all it's important to note that
the grades
and levels of school are different in
different countries
in the u.s most people start middle
school when they're 12 years old
at this age people are in 7th grade
most middle schools in the u.s include
7th
and 8th grade but there are some that go
from
6th to 8th grade in other countries
this might not be the case so one of the
big
changes that happens in middle school is
that students start going to multiple
classes with different teachers
in elementary school students have only
one teacher
who teaches every subject this also
means that they're with the same
classmates
all day however in american middle
schools
students usually have six or seven
different teachers and classes
this is a huge transition if you ask me
for some students this is overwhelming
and it's hard for them to do
well in every class when i started
middle school
i struggled a little bit with the amount
of homework i had
it was the first time in my life that i
had
more than an hour of homework each day
and it was the first time in my life
that i had to do homework on weekends
it seemed like a lot of work to me
however
in many other countries students have
more
work than american students in my
opinion
school in the u.s isn't that hard
compared to some
other countries but one thing that is
hard in middle school
is adapting to the new social
environment
in elementary school you're with the
same classmates
every year but this changes in middle
school
suddenly there are many more students at
your school
most of the people in your grade are
from other
elementary schools so you don't know
them
i remember being nervous on my first day
of seventh grade
because it felt like i was starting over
again
another reason why it's challenging for
middle schoolers to socialize
is because they're going through puberty
puberty is the time in your life
when your body and mind change a lot
i remember this phase of my life very
well
it's a really awkward and uncomfortable
time
it changes the way people act and
socialize with others
so middle school can be a stressful time
for people
regarding academics middle school in the
u.s
isn't as important as high school your
performance in high school
affects your chances of getting into
different colleges
but middle school doesn't really matter
when it comes to applying to college
if you don't do well in middle school it
probably won't ruin your life
you can still do well in high school but
middle school is important
because you learn to be a better and
more mature
student you learn how to handle more
classes
and more work also the tests are harder
than in elementary school
you actually have to study and prepare
for exams
these are all skills that you can learn
while in middle school
lastly let's talk about some of the
different subjects that americans learn
in middle school some of my classes
included
english u.s history earth science
and algebra also students can take
a few electives which are optional
classes
for example i took art and guitar class
in seventh grade and i had an elective
class
called tech lab in 8th grade these
classes were pretty fun
one other optional class some of my
friends took
was spanish i didn't take spanish until
high school though
all right now i'm going to ask you some
questions about today's video
to see how well you understood number
one
how old are most americans when they
start middle school
number two what's one challenging thing
about middle school
and number three what's an elective okay
remember to sign up for our one dollar
listening practice seminars
and download the listening time podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
also subscribe to the channel click on
the bell
and follow us on instagram i'll see you
next time